<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>Perpetually Curious</title>
        <description>PerpCurio's diary entries and site updates.</description>
        <link>https://perpcurio.com</link>
        <atom:link href="https://perpcurio.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />

        <item>
            <title>MoonCat Vtuber Model Reveal</title>
            <description>Talking about recent projects.</description>
            <link>https://perpcurio.com/diary#20250120</link>
            <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I plowed through progress on my vtuber model project over the weekend. I don&#39;t have much to say other than I&#39;m so proud of how it&#39;s turned out. Here are some snippets of the process and the result of the model at this time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Importing the art into Live2d was a big milestone in the process. I was pleased with how it looked and everything imported without a hitch. At this stage MoonCat&#39;s eye were in the full moon phase.
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://perpcurio.com/img/diary/202501/live2d_import.webp&quot; alt=&quot;The initial import of the art into Live2d.&quot;&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;The initial import of the art into Live2d was great. There were a few things I improved during the processed and reimported the art, but there were no initial issues.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://perpcurio.com/img/diary/202501/parts_textures.webp&quot; alt=&quot;The model parts organized in Live2d.&quot;&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;Organizing the layers in the art stage really paid off. See how neat all the textures look.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://perpcurio.com/img/diary/202501/texture_atlas.webp&quot; alt=&quot;The texture atlas for MoonCat&#39;s model.&quot;&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;The texture atlas is so satisfying.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With all the art meshed and the texture atlas mapped I spent 2 days configuring the deformers, parameters, and physics. After all that, and redrawing the model&#39;s mouth, this is it! MoonCat is an animated model the works with motion capture.
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://perpcurio.com/img/diary/202501/moon_cat_model_demo.gif&quot; alt=&quot;MoonCat responding to camera tracking.&quot;&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;This gif recording shows the model responding to my movement via camera tracking software in Vtube Studio.&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last thing I&#39;ll leave this post with is a video I found deeply inspiring from a_lilian, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=LKcT-aQuIFs&quot;&gt;Microsoft broke my voice&lt;/a&gt;. The video essay is philosophical and immensely reflective. a_lilian shares how Microsoft changed her beloved TTS voice used for her online self, and the beautiful outcome of that loss. I&#39;m still sitting with thoughts on my digital self, my physical self, how I want to express both, and how I&#39;ve masked both. I haven&#39;t settled these feelings yet, but I was comforted by a_lilian&#39;s commentary and her community. Watching the video set a clear path for my next project. MoonCat will have a voice.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">diary-20250120</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 15:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
            <title>Mooncat, Animation, and WebGL</title>
            <description>Talking about recent projects.</description>
            <link>https://perpcurio.com/diary#20250113</link>
            <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;With my plan to make a vtuber model, I researched and practiced several tangent skills last week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Web GL and Three.js&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you may have read, if you&#39;re visiting from Neocities or Nekoweb, I want to make my entry page look like a video game menu or start screen. Currently two links prompt the user to take the portal or turn around. This is my concept&#39;s simple basis: theme the page around a portal with these intentions:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inform the user of important info before entering the site (e.g., they&#39;re leaving the community site to go to perpcurio.com)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provide an interactive choice that transports the user one way or the other.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With that idea in mind, I have two approaches I&#39;m considering:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A game menu design with a partly animated background, the menu options would be the choice to take the portal or go back&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A start screen where the user moves an avatar in the direction of their choice, to the portal or back where they came from&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first option would be much easier to implement but has less interactivity for the user. The second option would be sick, but it requires me to learn about techniques for browser graphics and may not work on mobile at all. I like the second idea, and whether I can accomplish it or not, I want to try. So, I started reading and watching videos about WebGL and Three.js. I&#39;ve only dedicated a couple hours to this so far, but got a little playground environment created.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://perpcurio.com/img/diary/202501/threejs-demo.gif&quot; alt=&quot;A Three.js demo.&quot;&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;A spaghetti-o in space.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Drawing Moon Cat&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve drawn Mooncat several times this week and developed a few more features about my little character.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;irises are the moon in different phases depending on emotion/lighting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 or 3 whiskers on each side of their face.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;does NOT have a square body&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://perpcurio.com/img/diary/202501/moon_cat_square_body.webp&quot; alt=&quot;A sketch of Mooncat with a cubic body.&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;The cubic body isn&#39;t really working is it...&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mooncat is likely to be the first model I try to rig in Live2D, once I figure out a body design. I still have ideas for a model for my persona, but I want to go really simple at first. Mooncat is perfect for that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Animation&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My only experience with animation is making very simple gif emojis in Procreate. Like the gif of Mooncat in the gify pet feature on my home page I made in procreate. From the vtuber tutorials I ended up watching a bunch of animation tutorials and trying out a few simple exercises. I... um... LOVE animation. Animated shows make up the majority of what &quot;TV&quot; I watch. The possibility of using a software like Live2D to make my own animated shorts is interesting to put it lightly. But anyway... Behold Mooncat yawning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://perpcurio.com/img/diary/202501/moon_cat_yawn.webp&quot; alt=&quot;An animation of Mooncat yawning.&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Mooncat is eepy. Mooncat want nap.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">diary-20250113</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 21:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>