<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>Perpetually Curious</title>
        <description>PerpCurio's diary entries and site updates.</description>
        <link>https://perpcurio.com</link>
        <atom:link href="https://perpcurio.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />

        <item>
            <title>When They Won't Let You Cook</title>
            <description>10 pm, Realizing I've become the miserable smart ass and I'm not even 35 yet.</description>
            <link>https://perpcurio.com/diary#20250211</link>
            <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Work has drained so much out of me the past few weeks. In my 10 years of professional software development, the majority 7 years has been at tech startups, 6 of those years were at my first company where I cut my teeth on not only software but hardware too, and worked my way up to Director of Software. For the past 3 years, give or take, I&#39;ve been working as a senior software engineer at a media company in the gaming industry. I was overqualified for the position, much more so than those hiring me realized. I happily took the opportunity because I was exceedingly interested in the game content they covered, and I also had no idea the struggles I was setting myself up for: the struggles that come with being overqualified, and my own struggles transitioning from the culture of a startup tech company to... well... any company that&#39;s not that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First and foremost, I get bored all the time because I&#39;m only working on software, and in a narrow context. Which that would be fine, but outside of being at a company where I&#39;m surrounded by people (not just the engineers) that are passionate about software, I find it not nearly as stimulating. Along with the boredom, I&#39;m often either underestimated or not approached about subjects I have past hands-on experience with that no one else in the company does. This has started to improve some recently as I&#39;ve been more vocal about when I have expertise on something, whether I&#39;m being asked about it directly or not. But in general it&#39;s very one-lane, far from the many hats I&#39;m used to wearing. And the third thing to round out my moaning list of work laments, it&#39;s so fucking corporate that I feel like I can&#39;t breathe sometimes. The pace of executing an initiative or project is painfully slow for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With those struggles, and many other unsaid frustrations, I&#39;m trying to ensure I allocate my energy in ways that are good for me. If projects won&#39;t progress quickly at work, that&#39;s fine, I won&#39;t battle it. I&#39;ll do my work then focus my energy on my own projects. There&#39;s never a shortage of things I&#39;m cooking on... building keyboards and computers, electronics tinkering, drawing and animations, and even DIY house projects now that my partner and I have our own place. This weekend I replaced a light fixture in my staircase. +1 New skill.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">diary-20250211</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2025 22:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
            <title>Thought Soup</title>
            <description>My brain is fried from the week. I'm too tired to write a lot, random thought soup instead.</description>
            <link>https://perpcurio.com/diary#20250126</link>
            <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;My brain is fried from the week. I&#39;m too tired to write a lot, random thought soup instead.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I won&#39;t join blue sky, but at least they have an rss link for users so I can keep up with some people on there.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PL-uopgYBi65HwiiDR9Y23lomAkGr9mm-S&quot;&gt;Helluva Boss&lt;/a&gt; is an awesome NSFW cartoon on youtube.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Love my linux machine, but my desk is getting crowded with 2 pairs of keyboard and mouse + my drawing tablet :/&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All prepped to mod my steam deck with a new shell whenever I have a suitable weekend.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maybe I&#39;ll post on youtube since I have a vtuber model ready.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;WoW is still pretty boring. I&#39;m just logging in to do weekly time walking and playing other games instead.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Halftones in CSS are fucking cool.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Purple is the best color.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When will I have top surgery this year? I don&#39;t know yet, hospitals are scary.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When I was in high school I wanted to be a lot of things, 2 that I remember well are architect and tattoo artist.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://perpcurio.com/img/diary/202501/nightsky.webp&quot; alt=&quot;A blank and piink sketch.&quot;&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;An absent-minded digital sketch from this week.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">diary-20250126</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2025 20:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
            <title>MoonCat Vtuber Model Reveal</title>
            <description>Talking about recent projects.</description>
            <link>https://perpcurio.com/diary#20250120</link>
            <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I plowed through progress on my vtuber model project over the weekend. I don&#39;t have much to say other than I&#39;m so proud of how it&#39;s turned out. Here are some snippets of the process and the result of the model at this time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Importing the art into Live2d was a big milestone in the process. I was pleased with how it looked and everything imported without a hitch. At this stage MoonCat&#39;s eye were in the full moon phase.
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://perpcurio.com/img/diary/202501/live2d_import.webp&quot; alt=&quot;The initial import of the art into Live2d.&quot;&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;The initial import of the art into Live2d was great. There were a few things I improved during the processed and reimported the art, but there were no initial issues.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://perpcurio.com/img/diary/202501/parts_textures.webp&quot; alt=&quot;The model parts organized in Live2d.&quot;&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;Organizing the layers in the art stage really paid off. See how neat all the textures look.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://perpcurio.com/img/diary/202501/texture_atlas.webp&quot; alt=&quot;The texture atlas for MoonCat&#39;s model.&quot;&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;The texture atlas is so satisfying.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With all the art meshed and the texture atlas mapped I spent 2 days configuring the deformers, parameters, and physics. After all that, and redrawing the model&#39;s mouth, this is it! MoonCat is an animated model the works with motion capture.
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://perpcurio.com/img/diary/202501/moon_cat_model_demo.gif&quot; alt=&quot;MoonCat responding to camera tracking.&quot;&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;This gif recording shows the model responding to my movement via camera tracking software in Vtube Studio.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last thing I&#39;ll leave this post with is a video I found deeply inspiring from a_lilian, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=LKcT-aQuIFs&quot;&gt;Microsoft broke my voice&lt;/a&gt;. The video essay is philosophical and immensely reflective. a_lilian shares how Microsoft changed her beloved TTS voice used for her online self, and the beautiful outcome of that loss. I&#39;m still sitting with thoughts on my digital self, my physical self, how I want to express both, and how I&#39;ve masked both. I haven&#39;t settled these feelings yet, but I was comforted by a_lilian&#39;s commentary and her community. Watching the video set a clear path for my next project. MoonCat will have a voice.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">diary-20250120</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 15:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
            <title>MoonCat, Animation, and WebGL</title>
            <description>Talking about recent projects.</description>
            <link>https://perpcurio.com/diary#20250113</link>
            <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;With my plan to make a vtuber model, I researched and practiced several tangent skills last week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Web GL and Three.js&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you may have read, if you&#39;re visiting from Neocities or Nekoweb, I want to make my entry page look like a video game menu or start screen. Currently two links prompt the user to take the portal or turn around. This is my concept&#39;s simple basis: theme the page around a portal with these intentions:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inform the user of important info before entering the site (e.g., they&#39;re leaving the community site to go to perpcurio.com)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provide an interactive choice that transports the user one way or the other.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With that idea in mind, I have two approaches I&#39;m considering:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A game menu design with a partly animated background, the menu options would be the choice to take the portal or go back&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A start screen where the user moves an avatar in the direction of their choice, to the portal or back where they came from&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first option would be much easier to implement but has less interactivity for the user. The second option would be sick, but it requires me to learn about techniques for browser graphics and may not work on mobile at all. I like the second idea, and whether I can accomplish it or not, I want to try. So, I started reading and watching videos about WebGL and Three.js. I&#39;ve only dedicated a couple hours to this so far, but got a little playground environment created.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://perpcurio.com/img/diary/202501/threejs-demo.gif&quot; alt=&quot;A Three.js demo.&quot;&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;A spaghetti-o in space.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Drawing MoonCat&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve drawn MoonCat several times this week and developed a few more features about my little character.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;irises are the moon in different phases depending on emotion/lighting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 or 3 whiskers on each side of their face.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;does NOT have a square body&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://perpcurio.com/img/diary/202501/moon_cat_square_body.webp&quot; alt=&quot;A sketch of MoonCat with a cubic body.&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;The cubic body isn&#39;t really working is it...&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MoonCat is likely to be the first model I try to rig in Live2D, once I figure out a body design. I still have ideas for a model for my persona, but I want to go really simple at first. MoonCat is perfect for that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Animation&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My only experience with animation is making very simple gif emojis in Procreate. Like the gif of MoonCat in the gify pet feature on my home page I made in procreate. From the vtuber tutorials I ended up watching a bunch of animation tutorials and trying out a few simple exercises. I... um... LOVE animation. Animated shows make up the majority of what &quot;TV&quot; I watch. The possibility of using a software like Live2D to make my own animated shorts is interesting to put it lightly. But anyway... Behold MoonCat yawning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://perpcurio.com/img/diary/202501/moon_cat_yawn.webp&quot; alt=&quot;An animation of MoonCat yawning.&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;MoonCat is eepy. MoonCat want nap.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">diary-20250113</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 21:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
